# Milan Maheshwari

## **Product and Experience Designer**

I am a 20-year young digital Product Design enthusiast from Indian Institute of Technology, Roorkee. I have over 2.5 years worth of experience in problem solving through design. I am passionate in applying design principles to create wonderful user experiences keeping business in mind.

## **Work Experience**

## BlackBuck / Product Design Internship

MAY 2018 - JULY 2018, BENGALURU

Designed a fleet management mobile application for truck owners. Brainstormed ideas based on user research considering various user scenarios. Followed a data-driven design process to deliver high fidelity interfaces and interactions incorporating usability test findings. Collaborated with development and management teams to drive the product to launch.

## **Smartify / UI/UX** Design Internship

DECEMBER 2017 - JANUARY 2018, AHMEDABAD

Designed a smart home application to control all smart devices irrespective of their brand. Key tasks included understanding the problem, ideating solutions, user research, wireframing, designing user interfaces and interactions of the app.

### SDSLabs / UI/UX Designer, Frontend Developer

JAN 2017 - PRESENT, IIT ROORKEE

Working with a team of 12 designers and 35 developers to foster technical activities on the campus. We regularly organise lectures, workshops, competetions, hackathons and build applications for the people of IIT Roorkee.

#### **EDC IITR /** Executive Member

AUG 2017 - AUG 2018, IIT ROORKEE

Worked with EDC IITR to promote the spirit of innovation and entrepreneurship on the campus. Contributed in the organization of TEDx IIT Roorkee, 2017 and E-Summit, 2018.

milanmundra98@gmail.com +91 9468695111 linkedin.com/in/milan98

dribbble.com/milanmundra98 medium.com/@milanmundra98 behance.net/milanmundr0322

facebook.com/milanmundra98 twitter.com/milanmundra98

#### Skills

Design: Illustration and UI graphics with Illustrator & Photoshop • User flows • Concept sketches • Wireframes & mock ups with Sketch, Figma & Adobe XD • Motion design with After Effects • Style guides & pattern library

Prototyping: Rapid prototyping using Invision • Interactive user interfaces with Principle & After Effects • Front-end development with HTML/ CSS/ Javascript

Research: Contextual inquiries & user interviews • Persona hypothesis • User path scenarios • Usability analysis

#### Education

#### **IIT Roorkee /** B.Tech

JULY 2016 - PRESENT, ROORKEE

#### CBSE / Class 12 Board

2016, AJMER

#### **Hobbies / Interests**

Reading books • Travelling • Video Games Sketching • Writing • Photography